Hello everyone, welcome to English Pod.
My name is Marco.
And I'm Erica.
And today with Erica, we have a
very aggressive lesson for you today.
That's true.
We've got a revolutionary lesson.
Yesterday at English Pod, we're protesting.
So, Erica, why don't you
tell us what a protest is?
Well, when you protest
something, you go
into the streets and
show your disagreement.
Right, and you yell and you have
signs and everyone's just protesting.
And the news comes
and if it's not clear now,
it'll be clear after
the dialogue, I'm sure.
Definitely, definitely.
So, why don't we start
with our vocabulary preview?
Very capillary preview.
We have two words in our
vocabulary preview today.
The first is bankrupt.
Bankrupt.
So, if a company goes
bankrupt, what happens?
It means the company
doesn't have any more money.
So, it can't pay salaries.
It can pay, it can pay its bills, yeah.
So, basically, if it's bankrupt,
it's probably going to close.
Exactly.
Okay, our second word today is bailout.
Bailout.
B-A-I-L.
So, bailout is when the
government gives money
to a company that is
about to go bankrupt.
That's true, it's emergency money
that will help save the company.
Well, these two words are
taken directly from our dialogue.
And in today's dialogue, we're
going to bring you live to a newscast.
Right.
So, why don't we just
listen to the dialogue?
This is Action 5 news reporter Sarah
O'Connell reporting live from Washington, D.C.
where protests has broken out, thousands of
angry citizens are protesting against the
proposed bailout of the
auto-manufacturing industry.
Sir.
Sarah O'Connell.
Tell us five news.
Can you tell us what's happening?
Yeah.
We're here because we
feel this is an injustice.
But financially, responsibility
of big business has to stop.
We're here to show the
government that we don't
like the way they're
spending our tax dollars.
Sir.
But what exactly is
making everyone so angry?
It's an absolute outrage, Sarah.
The U.S. government
wants to give $25 billion
of taxpayers money
to the auto industry.
These are companies that have been
mismanaged and are now nearly bankrupt.
I see.
But many supporters
of the bailout argue that
it could help save the jobs of
millions of hardware from Americans.
That may be true.
And I, for what don't want
to see anyone lose their job.
But how can these CEOs ask for a bailout
when they're making millions of dollars?
And then they have the nerve to
fly to Washington in private jets.
This costs hundreds
of thousands of dollars.
They're asking for money.
That is just not right.
Good point.
This is Sarah O'Connell reporting live
from Washington, D.C. back to Utah.
Wow, these people are really angry.
I think they're furious.
Well, I think they have some good
points and we'll talk about that later.
But now it's time for language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
Yeah, there was some great
language in this dialogue.
A lot of language we
use to express our anger.
Right.
And one of those words and the first
one for language takeaway is injustice.
Injustice.
And injustice.
So an injustice is
something that isn't fair.
It's totally unfair.
It's unfair, yeah.
This is an injustice.
Let's look at our second word.
Outrage.
And outrage.
So Erica, why don't you give us an
example on how you would use outrage?
There's no more coffee.
This is an outrage.
Yeah, there we go.
That's an outrage.
Okay.
Let's go to our next word now.
Break out.
So we have some great
examples on how we use break out.
So let's listen.
Example one.
War is broken out in
Antarctica as countries of
the world fight for
control of the icy continent.
Example two.
Officials are warning that fighting
could break out in the border regions.
Example three.
A forest fire broke out last night.
Well, this is a wonderful phrasal
verb that means to begin suddenly.
Okay.
So I think that's pretty clear.
Yep.
Break out.
Let's go to our next word now.
Mismanaged.
So when something is mismanaged,
it's not managed properly.
Managed poorly.
Poorly, right.
Yeah.
Our final word today is.
Have the nerve tube.
I think this one also is a
little bit difficult to understand.
Yeah.
But we have some great
examples prepared for you.
So let's listen to them.
Example one.
I've been in love with
you since the third
grade, but I didn't
have the love to tell you.
Example two.
I don't believe it.
You have the nerve to ask me for money.
When you know I've just lost my job.
Example three.
What?
Do you have the nerve to bring
your new girlfriend to visit my mother?
So have the nerve tube is like
dare to do something, right?
Yeah, how dare you?
Yeah.
Have the nerve to.
It's like I can't believe
you would do that.
Yeah, I think that's quite clear.
Yeah.
Okay.
A lot of great words in our dialogue today.
And also we have some really
interesting grammar in today's dialogue.
Right.
So today let's look at
some grammar breakdown.
Grammar breakdown.
In this section, grammar breakdown,
we show you a particular grammar
structure and explain a little bit about
how that structure affects meaning.
So it's not really about getting
the grammar perfectly right.
It's about understanding the meaning.
Right.
And in today's lesson,
we saw some really great
examples on how we use
the present perfect tense.
Let's listen to an example
from the dialogue.
We're a protest has broken out.
See the verb here break out like a protest
has broken out happened in the past, right?
Right.
And it's still going on now.
Exactly.
So present perfect is used
when we're talking about a
event that happened in the
past and is continuing on now.
Exactly.
Or is continuing to affect now.
I think that's pretty clear.
Yeah, but now if you want to indicate
or if you want to demonstrate that
the action has finished, the event is
over, then you would say it like this.
A protest broke out.
This form, you see
that the protest is over.
It happened yesterday already.
Right, and I think it's
really emphasizing the fact
that it is no longer affecting
the present moment.
Exactly.
So remember the difference between
present perfect and simple past.
Now if you want to know more
about these tenses present perfect
and simple past, be sure to go
to our website at EnglishPod.com.
In the grammar section, you can
find some more great examples
and a really clear explanation
on how these tenses are formed.
But now we are ready to listen
to our dialogue a second time.
The auto manufacturing industry.
Sir.
Sir O'Connell.
To have five news.
Can you tell us what's happening?
Yeah.
We're here because we
feel this is an injustice.
The financially responsibility
of big business has to stop.
We're here to show the
government that we don't
like the way they're
spending our tax dollars.
Sir, but what exactly is
making everyone so angry?
It's an absolute outrage, sir,
the US government wants to
give $25 billion of taxpayers'
money to the auto industry.
These are companies that have been
mismanaged and are now nearly bankrupt.
I see.
By many supporters of the
bailout, argue that it could
help save the jobs of millions
of hard work in Americans.
That may be true.
And I, for what don't want
to see anyone lose their job.
But how can these CEOs ask for a bailout
when they're making millions of dollars?
And then they have the nerve to
fly to Washington in private jets.
This costs hundreds
of thousands of dollars.
They're asking for money.
That is just not right.
Good point.
This is Sir O'Connell reporting live
from Washington, D.C., back to Utah.
Okay, Erica.
So what do you think about this situation?
About the bailout of the auto industry.
Yes.
I think it's a bad idea.
Why?
There's so many reasons.
I mean, I don't think it's
fair for us as taxpayers.
Well, I guess I'm not
really an American taxpayer.
But I don't think it's
fair for the taxpayers to
have to pay for the
mismanagement of these companies.
I mean, they've got so much debt.
They've produced cars that
nobody really wants to buy.
And now they're in trouble.
And it's not our money that
should be spent on saving them.
Yeah, I would agree with you
on that, but you do have to take
into consideration the fact that
if these companies go bankrupt,
thousands of people
will lose their jobs, and
not only the people
that work at the factories,
but also people that work for other
companies that supply these factories.
Yeah, I mean, I see what
you're saying, Marco.
But at the same time, we can't support
an industry that isn't working properly.
I mean, if one of these companies
goes bankrupt, it's going to be terrible.
But it will force the other two
companies, perhaps, to manage
themselves better to streamline
and become more efficient.
I just think it will be
better in the future.
Well, it could be, but also maybe
all three companies can go bankrupt.
It would be sad because
the American car, the
American auto industry,
is a symbol of prosperity.
It's also the symbol of like
the American culture in general.
I guess that's true.
So, so it would be a shame
for it to go bankrupt because
everyone owns a car in the
United States or most people.
And it's just something that we can't lose.
But it is an interesting topic, and we
also want to know your opinions about this.
Yeah, listeners, please come to
our website at www.EnglishPod.
com and tell us what you think
about this bailout and about this lesson.
On the website, we'll post a link
to the news article where you can
read a little bit more about this
because this is actually going on now.
That's true.
Well, everyone, thanks for listening,
and until next time, goodbye.